# Chenjun Xu

Personal Web: chenjux.github.io | chenjux@uw.edu

#### **Research Focus**

My research focuses on the application of Large Language Models (LLMs), particularly on the interaction between humans and LLMs. A key area of interest is the overconfidence exhibited by LLMs, where they may provide information with high certainty despite the potential for inaccuracy. I aim to apply LLM technology to improve human health, leveraging these models to enhance healthcare outcomes, patient experiences, and decision-making processes within the medical field. By addressing the overconfidence issue, I hope to create more reliable, safe, and trustworthy AI systems that can effectively support healthcare professionals and patients alike.

#### Education

#### UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, INFORMATION SCHOOL

2022/9 - 2024/6

Master of Information Management with Specialization in Data Science

Seattle, WA

• Relevant coursework: Data Science, Relational Database, Large Language Models, Machine Learning, Data Mining

#### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE

2017/09 - 2021/06

Bachelor of Science in Physics with Specialization in Computational Physics

Irvine, CA

• Relevant coursework: Computer Science, Calculus and Differential Equations(ODEs,PDEs), Numerical Analysis

#### **Honors and Awards**

• Social Impact & Social Justice Award(University of Washington)

2024

# **Research Experience**

#### **LLM & Overconfidence**

2024 - Present

Advised by: Bill Howe

- Participated in research and development activities, including comprehensive literature review, experiment design, and preliminary testing phases. Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to investigate the differences and similarities in overconfidence between humans and large language models.
- Actively exploring on the difference and similarity of overconfidence between large language models and human
  in answering benchmark questions, utilizing advanced natural language processing techniques and machine learning
  frameworks. Engaged in data collection, analysis, and interpretation to assess the effects of fine-tuning on model
  performance.

#### LLM & Medical Image & Mental Health

2024 - Present

Advised by: Peiwu Qin

- Contributed to retinal fundus image analysis for predicting conditions like high blood pressure and pathological myopia, especially in data preprocessing and feature extractions.
- Explored LLMs for mental illness diagnosis, including developing a prompt-based approach to reduce reasoning hallucinations and improve reliability.
- Enhanced patient safety by proposing LLM confidence scoring techniques, transforming 15% of hallucinations into acknowledgments of uncertainty, and mitigating risks of AI-induced misdiagnoses.

### **Publications/Preprint**

- Know Your Limits: A Survey of Abstention in Large Language Models
- Wen, Bingbing, Jihan Yao, Shangbin Feng, Chenjun Xu, Yulia Tsvetkov, Bill Howe, and Lucy Lu Wang.
- TACL 2024 in proceeding
- Mitigating Overconfidence in Large Language Models: A Behavioral Lens on Confidence Estimation and Calibration
- Bingbing Wen, Chenjun Xu, HAN Bin, Robert Wolfe, Lucy Lu Wang, Bill Howe.
- NeurIPS 2024 Workshop on Behavioral ML in proceeding

# **Coursework Projects**

# Capstone Project: AI Potential with Service Requests and Incidents Social Impact & Social Justice Award

2023 - 2024

- Fine-tuned and Deployed Meta Llama 2 LLM Model within the Seattle Government IT infrastructure to optimize task management and streamline agenda tracking processes.
- Integrated the LLM with the department's agenda database, enabling seamless communication and data exchange between the LLM and existing database infrastructure. It is planned to allow 1000+ Seattle government employees to use LLM, with a utilization rate of 60% and a 30% improvement in work efficiency.

#### Graduate AI cloud service coursework

2023

- Deployed and managed an AI-driven MedCamp website using Microsoft Azure's App Service to predict individuals' health check-up needs, alleviating pressure on limited health resources.
- Established and maintained a high-availability, scalable Azure server environment for the deployed website.
- Implemented best practices for code versioning, testing, and deployment on GitHub, optimizing the development workflow and minimizing downtime.

#### **Presentations**

• iSchool Founding Board Meeting(University of Washington): AI Potential with Service Requests and Incidents

2024

# **Working Experience**

#### Data Engineer at SuperMap

2021-2022

- Developed data pipelines and automation tools that saved 30% time on website data migration between multiple servers, resulting in faster project completion and increased team productivity.
- Collaborated with a cross-functional team of data scientists, engineers, and stakeholders to design and develop a smart city maps data warehouse and ETL that enabled data-driven decision-making on critical issues such as COVID-19 pandemic control, urban plumbing system, and aging population.
- Set up servers on Aliyun using Docker and migrated 1TB map data. Achieved daily warehouse data updates through writing SQL triggers. Fetched, synchronized, and updated data among several PostgreSQL and Oracle databases with Dolphin Scheduler. Exploited Python to solve data management problems and improved speed of sorting out data by 20%.